听我说 各位
Listen up, everybody.
有一件小怪事
Something strange is afoot.
别对自己这么严苛 阿憨
Don't be hard on yourself, Han.
你比小怪稍微高一点啦
You're taller than a foot.
怎么了
What's wrong?
又有人把你当弥勒佛 摸你肚子求平安吗
Somebody rub your belly for luck again?
不是 是我觉得我失忆了
No, I think I might be losing my memory.
根据我的付费网络台观看记录
According to Netflix, last night I watched
我看了1.5部《飓风营救》和《潜伏》123
half the "Taken"s and all the "Insidious"es-es.
3部全看了
All of them!
别紧张 你可能梦游时看了
Relax. You probably just sleep-watched them.
你梦游时可能还顺便
And you probably also sleep-ordered
在亚马逊网购了28盒卫生棉条
28 boxes of tampons on Amazon.
麦克斯 你黑进我的账号啊
Max, you hacked into my accounts?
这可是犯法的呀
That's illegal!
而且还超出了我对你智商的判断
And beyond what I thought you were intellectually capable of!
猜你那种密码哪能算黑啊
Not much of a hack when the password is
"憨情时速"
"Hanstoppable."
姑娘们 你们这是违背他的信任啊
That's a breach of trust, girls.
你们帮我订购那鞋子了吗
Did you order me those shoes?
靠 早知道我密码用"憨色池塘"了
Dammit! I should have gone with "Han Golden Pond."
太阳从西边出来了
Oh, this is weird.
我收到一条伯纳德的语音留言
There's a message from Bernard,
他是我奶奶的管家
my grandmother's butler.
他怎么会找我
Why would he be calling me?
可能手机在裤"管"里压到了
Maybe he butler-dialed you.
卡洛琳 你好吗
Caroline, hello.
我是替你奶奶打这通电话
I'm calling on behalf of your grandmother.
她理由都不给一个就抛下我四年
Wait, she abandons me after four years with no explanation
她现在居然好意思来找我
and now she reaches out?
我都沦落到这样了
Now?
说什么理由都没用
There is no excuse for that.
她这几年陷入昏迷了
She's been in a coma.
好吧 看来有一个理由有用
Okay, there's one excuse for that.
她现在醒了 想见你
But she's awake now and wants to see you.
麦克斯 她想见我
Max, she wants to see me.
我去打电话联系他
I'm going to go call him.
她不是避而不见 而是半个身子进鬼门关了
She didn't shun me, she was just practically dead!
麦克斯 能问问你的意见吗
Max, can I ask your opinion about something?
如果我跟苏菲想要宝宝
If Sophie and I want to get pregnant,
她就需要服药
she needs to be on drugs.
嗑嗨了才愿意跟你搞吗 我明白
Oh, to have sex with you? I get that.
不是 是助孕药
No, fertility drugs.
我上一次在性事上面花这么多钱
I haven't paid this much for sex
是08年杂交盛宴游轮票
since Orgy Cruise '08.
所以我想求阿憨给我加薪
So I'm going to ask Han for a raise.
你觉得有戏吗
What do you think?
我觉得会是一场精彩的好剧
I think that'll be fun to watch.
我想出一个新密码了
Well, I've come up with a new password
你们绝对猜不到
that none of you will ever guess.
《憨娜·蒙塔娜》
Han-ah Montana?
我靠
Dammit!
阿憨今天很帅哦
Lookin' good, Han.
你去知名成人西服店买衣服了吗
Have you been shopping at Men's Wearhouse?
就爱你这范儿[广告语]
'Cause I like the way you look.
你明知道我只去另一家折扣服饰店
You know I exclusively shop at T.J. Maxx.
每年就靠它们让我挥别春季 喜迎夏季
They've been helping me spring into summer for years.
大家安安
Hey, everybody!
奥列格 咋样了
Oleg, what happened?
你让泡菜妹给你加薪了吗
Did you ask that little Korean girl for a raise?
麦克斯 我奶奶让我明天去见她
Max, my grandmother wants me to come and see her tomorrow!
好兴奋啊
This is so exciting.
我家族还有其他没被关进联邦监狱的活人
Someone in my family is alive and not in federal prison.
的确让人兴奋
That is exciting.
你觉得我们能捞到多少银子
How much money do you think we're getting?
她有钱对吧
She's rich, right?
真不敢相信这些年她居然是昏迷了
I can't believe all this time she was in a coma.
我也不敢相信你认识昏迷的人
I can't believe you knew someone in a coma
却没给我机会在他们脸上画胡子
and I didn't get to draw a mustache on them.
你好啊 卡洛琳
Hello, Caroline.
你奶奶的家很豪华嘛
Your grandmother's place is fancy.
我就直说出来吧
I'm just gonna say it.
我觉得没人在那台电梯里撒过尿呢
I don't think anybody has ever peed in there.
伯纳德
Bernard!
岁月没在你脸上留下一点痕迹啊
You haven't aged at all.
谢谢
Thank you.
毕竟她睡了四年 没空守她的面霜
She hasn't been awake to guard her creams.
这里让我想起好多童年回忆
Oh, this brings back so many childhood memories.
以前我们的4.2米高圣诞树就摆这里
Right here is where we had our 14-foot Christmas tree.
而奶奶就是在这里给我一年一度的抱抱
And then right here is where she'd give me her yearly hug.
卡洛琳 你从丑闻的谷底反弹回来了吗
Well, Caroline, have you bounced back from the scandal?
如果在餐厅打工 睡折叠床
If you count working at a diner, sleeping in a wall,
上在线药房买衣服算反弹
and clothes shopping at CVS,
那她弹力超足
then she's real bouncy.
这位是你的同性伴侣吗
And is this your same-sex partner?
如果遗产有我一份 那我就是
I will be if that gets me in the will.
伯纳德 她是麦克斯 我的室友
Bernard, this is Max. She's my roommate.
我们那个年代就这么"称呼"
Yes, that's what we called them back in the day.
她发现呼唤铃了
Oh, she's found the bell.
我"走大运"啊
Lucky me.
但刚才只是摇一下
But that was just a single dingle.
单摇是警告
A warning dingle.
双摇就喊救命啦
Double dingle. Mayday.
阿斯特丽德奶奶 是我 卡洛琳
Grammy Astrid, it's Caroline!
亲爱的 我知道
I know, darling.
我只是老 又不是瞎
I'm old, not blind.
人家好想好想你
I've missed you so much.
小心点 别把她弄太兴奋
Careful. Don't get her overexcited.
开窗 貌似闻到有个屁精在房里
Crack a window. Smells like Ass-trid in here.
我的确是该把体力留给
I suppose I should conserve my energy
你要为我办的午宴上
for the luncheon you're going to throw me.
什么午宴
What luncheon now?
你将要为她办的那个
The one you're going to throw
重回社交圈午宴啊
to re-introduce her to society,
有点类似出场[柜]派对
a sort of coming out party.
这不应该是你的专业领域吗
Isn't that more your turf?
奶奶 我也很乐意为你办午宴
Grammy, I'd be happy to throw you a luncheon
可是我付...
but I can't afford--
抱歉 卡洛琳 别在意那些事
Sorry. Caroline, never mind all that.
应该先介绍朋友
Introductions are in order.
奶奶 这位是我的朋友 麦克斯
Oh, Grammy. This is my friend, Max.
这个嘛... 欢迎醒来
Hey, uh, I guess, welcome back.
卡洛琳 你真是一点都没变
You haven't changed a bit, Caroline.
总是跟佣人们交朋友
Always making friends with the help.
是叫玛丽亚是吧
Maria, was it?
用高脚杯给我装杯水来 麻烦啦[西语]
I'll take a tall glass of agua, por favor.
希望我背后有这位玛丽亚
Hoping there's a Maria behind me.
卡洛琳 你好吗
Caroline, how have you been?
你成为华尔街之王了吗
Are you running Wall Street yet?
没 但我给自己剪了头发
No, but I did cut my hair,
这可是件又惊又喜的事
which was scary but rewarding.
奶奶 今非昔比 自从我失...
Grammy, a lot has changed since I lost all my--
说真的 兄弟 去检查下肺好吗
Seriously, dude, get an x-ray.
现在立刻跟我出来
Outside. Now.
还在等那杯水呢 玛丽亚
And still waiting on that agua, Maria.
好啦好啦好啦[西语]
Ay, yi yi.
好了 伯纳德 你是在鬼哭狼嚎啥
Okay, Bernard, what's with the "Gahs"?
我说话时你打断我的频繁度
You interrupted what I was saying so often,
差点让我以为我们是夫妻
it's like we're a married couple.
我是在阻止你
I was trying to stop you
提起你爸爸陷入的那个丑闻
from mentioning your father's scandal.
原来啊 我还以为那是英国人独特放屁方法
Oh, I thought that's just how British people fart.
你奶奶完全不知道那档事
Your grandmother has no memory of what happened.
而当我试着告诉她那坏消息时
When I attempted to tell her the bad news,
她就中风陷入昏迷了
she had a stroke and slipped into a coma.
我当时就说"你儿子好像有点麻烦"
I said, "Your son might be in some trouble,"
才这样 她就倒下了
and that was it; she was out.
她不知道我身无分文了吗
She doesn't know I lost all my money?
我知道 很惨
I know. It's terrible.
但更惨的是你得告诉她 她也身无分文了
And what's worse is you have to tell her she's lost all hers.
她破产了吗
She's broke?
那老娘干嘛还给她端水啊
Then why did I get her that water?
姑娘们 屏息以待
Hey, girls. Buckle up.
奥列格要再去求阿憨加薪了
Oleg's gonna ask Han for a raise again.
小心 热腾腾天菜驾到
Hot stuff, coming through.
快看 是翻版男厨牌 男畜牌大厨
Oh look, it's Chef Boy-Are-You-Gross.
帽子不错吧
Nice hat, right?
我们在床上玩角色扮演时他也会戴
He wears it in the bedroom when we role-play.
我是爱挑剔的客人
I'm the fussy customer,
而他会来我的"小饼干"上涂"奶油"
and he slathers butter on my biscuit.
全套服装不止这样
This isn't the whole costume.
我还会给我的"大雕"也戴一顶小帽子
I also wear a drumstick paper frill around my penis.
用"鸡"愉快
Boner appetit.
阿憨来了
Oh, here comes Han.
好戏登场啦
It's showtime, baby.
我想到了一个新密码
Well, I have a new password
绝对没人可以猜到
that no one will ever get.
"冲出憨普顿"吗
"Straight Outta Compt-Han"?
我靠
Dammit!
这菜好好吃啊
This food is so good.
不得不称赞雇用了这位厨师的那个天才
My compliments to the man who hired the chef.
奥列格 你不可能因为苏菲演得她吃了
Oleg, you're not getting a raise just because Sophie can act
你的食物很满意就获得加薪
like your food is yummy in her tummy.
如果我换个口音 你会改变主意吗
Would you change your mind if I did it in a different accent?
我以前在波兰当过女演员 我能学好多口音呢
I used to act in Poland. I can do a whole bunch.
我的老天
My word.
这意式饺子人间美味啊
I just love this tasty tortellini.
多谢你带给我一夜恶梦
Thank you for tonight's nightmare.
一个桌吗
Uh, table for one?
不用了 谢谢
Not for this one, thank you.
伯纳德 你好啊 你来这里干什么
Bernard, hi. What are you doing here?
我也想问你这个问题
I could ask the same of you and follow up
外加一连串关于这身制服的问题
with a series of questions about that hideous uniform.
看起来就像黄芥末跟番茄酱打了一架
Looks like mustard and ketchup had a fight
最后全都输了
and everyone lost.
干啥呢 老"伯" 你跟这里格格不入
What up, B-nard? You look even paler here.
而你跟这里简直"臭味相投"
And you look perfect here.
这是让你明天午宴穿的衣服
Now, something to wear for tomorrow's luncheon.
你奶奶旧的香奈儿套装
One of your grandmother's Chanel suits.
而这里是宾客表
Here's her guest list.
貌似只有一个人选了"会来"
I'm afraid only one guest RSVP'd "Yes."
其他人都选了"已死"
All the rest of her friends RSVP'd "Dead."
伯纳德 我真的很希望能满足奶奶的愿望
Bernard, I really do wish I could give my Grammy what she wants,
但我真的没有钱帮她办真的豪华午宴
but I don't have the money for a real fancy luncheon.
我连真的牛奶都喝不起
Or even real milk, for that matter.
我们都喝"类牛奶饮料"
We drink "milk drink."
我觉得她承受不起更多失望了
I don't think she can take much more disappointment.
今早我不得不告诉她 她最爱的运动员
This morning I had to tell her all about
布鲁斯·詹那的事[变性]
her favorite athlete, Bruce Jenner.
这也太凄惨了
This is so sad.
奶奶的一切都没了
Grammy's whole world is gone
而她还浑然不知
and she has no idea.
麦克斯 我起码得满足她这么一个心愿
Max, I have to give her the one thing that she wants.
重回白人之外皆无人权的年代吗
A major rollback on civil rights?
不是啦 是办午宴
No, the luncheon.
让她再开心最后一次吧
She deserves one last hurrah
之后再告诉她失去一切的真相
before I tell her she's lost everything.
真希望当年我的人生掉落谷底前
I wish someone had done that for me
也有人为我这么做
before my life came crashing down.
好吧 我会帮你
Okay, I'll help you.
应该是玛丽亚会帮你 前提是她能请到保姆看小孩
I mean, Maria will, if she can find a babysitter.
这身爆乳女仆装 我只为你一人穿
You are the only person I'll wear this for.
有没有那300块预付款都愿意
You know, without the $300 up front.
幸好苏菲有女仆装
Thank God Sophie had that maid outfit.
我觉得这身衣服能行
I think this is gonna work.
只要你不转身便万事大吉
As long as you don't turn around.
卡洛琳 是你吗
Caroline, is that you?
她要出来了 赶快
Oh, she's coming. Quick.
快去屏风后面 把套装套上
Behind the screen. Put the suit on over that.
你要我在一个屏风后面换上香奈儿套装吗
You want me to change into a Chanel suit behind this screen?
空间大着呢 我都干过无数次了
Oh, there's room. I've done it numerous times.
我们其余的员工来了吗
Oh, did the rest of our staff arrive yet?
来了 如果他们也算员工的话
Yes, if you can call them that.
话说你们从哪儿找来的这些奇人
Where did you find them anyway?
就附近啊
Um, around.
把我推到餐厅啊
Just push me into the room!
我已经尽力了
I'm doing the best I can!
这裤子大了整整五个号
These pants are five sizes too big!
伯纳德 下次不要雇童工了
Bernard, next time, don't hire a child butler.
还有你 难道中国没有轮椅吗
And you, don't they have wheelchairs in China?
我是泡菜国人好吗
I'm from Korea!
我觉得不像
I don't think so.
告诉卡洛琳她欠我一份大人情
Tell Caroline she owes me.
鬼知道穿奥列格的男仆装
Who knows what STD I'm catching
会害我染上什么性病
from Oleg's butler costume?
再说了 他怎么会有这种衣服
And why does he even have this?
这是他们玩《淫家屯》的戏服
It's from when they play "Going Downtown Abbey."
玛丽亚 我头发需要打理
Maria, I need help with my hair.
你来发挥吧
See what you can do.
不行 我不太擅长那方面
Um, no, I'm not really good at that.
玛丽亚 快去 帮她弄
Maria, just do it. Go.
好吧
Okay.
满足你一次 下不为例
You get one of those, and that was it.
这才是我的孙女 你看起来真美
Oh, there's my girl. You look wonderful.
我都忘了香奈儿的衣服质感有多好
I forgot how good Chanel feels against my skin.
感觉就像回到家
It's like coming home,
回到一个用丝绸和希望搭建的房子
but the house is made of silk and hope.
这样会太《星球大战》莱娅公主风吗
How's this? A little too Princess Leia?
上面 我喜欢在上面
On top! I like it up on top.
奶奶 不要这么少儿不宜好吗
Whoa, Grammy. Keep it PG.
我在哪里
Where am I?
格特鲁德·古尔斯比来了
Oh, it's Gertrude Goolsby.
您第一位也是唯一一位来的宾客
Your first and only guest has arrived.
阿斯特丽德
Astrid!
我必须得...
Oh, have to--oh.
悄然走近你
Sneaks up on you.
祝你一切顺利
Good luck with all this.
我会在厨房 学习墨西哥连锁餐厅的菜单
I'll be in the kitchen, studying the Chipotle menu.
为我下一份工作做准备
For my next job.
你看起来真美 阿斯特丽德
Don't you look smashing, Astrid.
我猜的 我已经看不见了
I'm assuming. I can't see anymore.
我猜你和奶奶
Well, I bet you and Grammy have
一定有很多趣事要叙叙旧
a lot of fun stuff to catch up on.
戈登还好吗
How is Gordon?
他得了脸癌
He has face cancer.
要不聊聊天气也行啊
Or the weather is also a subject.
我们希望马上上第一道菜
We'd like the first course, pronto.
玛丽亚 别一副死人样
Maria! Look alive.
彼此彼此
You're one to talk.
满足她一次 下不为例
And she gets one of those and that was it.
亲爱的 我能问你个问题吗
Dear, may I ask you a question?
我在哪里
Where am I?
还有我们的酒侍呢
Oh, and where is our sommelier?
随时为您效劳
At your service.
来点酒吗
Some wine?
是我失误 这瓶没了
My bad. This one's empty.
我等无聊了
I got bored.
您呢 夫人
And what about you, ma'am?
干白 干红
White, red,
还是你喜欢"干"巧克力棕
or maybe you prefer a chocolate brown?
原来我来到了新奥尔良
I must be in New Orleans.
找到了
Here we go.
这瓶是产自波尔多酒区
It's from the Bordeaux region.
更像是来自好市多超市区
More like the Costco region.
玛丽亚
Maria!
叫我啊
That's me.
为什么这些叉子都摆放错了
Why are these forks not laid out correctly?
玛丽亚 赶紧摆叉子
Maria, forks, now.
很高兴你喜欢我这身衣服
Glad you like that outfit,
因为它将会是你的寿服
'cause you're gonna be buried in it.
我把这瓶红酒拿到厨房醒醒酒
I think I'm gonna let this one breathe in the kitchen.
卡洛琳 我想见见主厨
Caroline, I'd like to meet the chef.
当然可以 主厨
Oh, of course. Chef!
各位好
Booyah!
我是奥列格主厨
I'm Chef Oleg.
曾有幸被地狱厨神锁头暴打的厨师
Gordon Ramsay once put me in a headlock.
请享用我第一道菜的第一道菜
Please enjoy the first course of my first course:
美味的意式饺子
a tasty tortellini.
卡洛琳 这个酱汁太好吃了
Caroline, this sauce is delicious!
很高兴你能喜欢
Oh, I'm so glad you like it.
这顿午宴就是要让你觉得
This is the kind of luncheon that makes you feel
你能承受随之而来的任何事物
like you can handle anything that comes along.
可惜没有更多宾客能一起享用
Pity there aren't more guests to enjoy it.
亲
Darling!
恕我姗姗来迟 希望还能赶上午宴
Well, I hope I'm not late for the luncheon!
这个法式布丁真是天赐之物
This creme brule is just divine!
千万别介意我随意点啊
Don't mind if I don't mind.
不好意思 我得嘘嘘
Uh, excuse me. I have to tinkle.
厕所[约翰]在哪里
Where's your john?
人家忘了嘛
Oh, I forgot!
好啦
Yes, um...
请见谅
Pardon me, yes.
麻烦告诉我您家的...
Could you direct me to your...
茅厕[约翰森]怎么走吗
Jonathan?
阿斯特丽德 亲爱的
Astrid, darling,
我之前不太确定你的午宴会是怎么样
I wasn't sure what to expect from one of your lunches,
毕竟自从那件丑闻后
you know, since the scandal,
你失去所有的...
since you lost all of your--
我是说
I mean, uh...
午宴结束啦 格特鲁德要走啦
Lunch is over. Gertrude is leaving.
丑闻 什么丑闻
Scandal? What scandal?
你懂的
Oh, you know.
你最深的恐惧 身无...
The horror of you not having any more--
救命 铃儿摇两下
Mayday! Double dingle!
玛丽亚 想想办法
Maria, do something.
所以你的意思是她不想谈论
So you mean she doesn't want to talk about the fact
她失去所有...
that she's lost all her mon--
摔碎的是水晶杯啊
Oh, it's crystal that broke.
我还以为是阿斯特丽德的老骨头呢
I thought it was one of Astrid's bones.
我会赔的啦 虽然我赔不起
I'll replace it. I mean, I can't,
但貌似当下这么说才对
but it's the right thing to say right now.
玛丽亚 那是我好的水晶杯
Maria, that's my good crystal.
它无可替代 不像你
And it's not replaceable, unlike you.
-给我出去 -好
- Now go! - Fine.
我马上走 去玛丽亚生活的地方
I'll go. To wherever Maria lives.
但我想告诉你 你的孙女
But just know your granddaughter
为了午宴完美 真的费尽心思
worked really hard to make this lunch all nice.
不 你不用走
No, you don't have to go.
那我能走吗
Oh, can I go?
或许我也该走
Maybe I should go too.
有人信我有安排吗
Would anyone buy that I had plans?
都不许走
No one is going.
我去把摔碎的水晶杯捡起来
I'm just gonna pick up the broken crystal
然后继续这场完美的午宴
and we'll just continue to have the best luncheon ever.
卡洛琳 让佣人去捡
Caroline! Let the help do that.
不许蹲在地上
Get up off of that floor!
你又不是他们中的一员
You are not one of them.
老实说 我是
Actually, yes, I am.
奶奶 或许你才从昏迷中醒来
Grammy, you may have been in a coma,
但我觉得刚大梦方醒的人是我
but I feel like it's me that just woke up.
在过去五年中
For the past five years,
我真的很想念这一切
I have been really missing all of this,
但让人生有意义的不是一个上好的水晶杯
but it's not good crystal that makes a life.
而是好人
It's good people.
像他们这样的人
People like them.
他们不是"佣人"
And they are not "the help,"
但他们却心甘情愿为我所"用"
but they did come here to help me.
或许我和你有血缘关系
'Cause you and I might be related,
但现在这些人才是我的家人
but these people are my family now.
还有 我该告诉你
And also, I should tell you,
我不在华尔街工作
I don't work on Wall Street.
我在布鲁克林的一家餐厅工作
I work in Brooklyn, in a diner.
瞧 我是一名服务员
See? I'm a waitress.
这点有待商议
That's debatable.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你可是钱宁家族的人
You're a Channing.
你怎么能去当服务员呢
How could you be a waitress?
因为这位千金 千金散尽
Because she lost all her money
而你也身无分文了
when you lost all your money.
卡洛琳 她在说什么
Caroline, what is she saying?
没什么 别听她的
Nothing, she's saying nothing.
我是说
I'm saying,
你是穷鬼
you're poor.
我就离开两分钟
Oh, I leave for two minutes
这派对就立马玩完啦
and the party really goes downhill!
你奶奶的事很遗憾 亲爱的
I'm sorry again about your grandma, darlin'.
多谢关心 厄尔
Thanks, Earl.
她也算死得其所了
Well, she did die doing what she loved:
当着富人 吼着佣人
being rich and yelling at the help.
我会超级想念她
I'm gonna miss her so much!
苏菲 你认识她不过三道菜的时间
Sophie, you knew her for three courses.
我知道 姐的波兰日间艾美奖可不是白得的
I know; I didn't win that Polish daytime Emmy for nothing!
卡洛琳 你为她举办午宴
You know, Caroline, you did the right thing
这事做得对
throwing that luncheon.
我的胯部拉伤了
And I pulled a glute
只因帮你那可爱的种族歧视奶奶推轮椅
pushing your lovely racist grandmother around.
我真的很感激你们帮我办这个午宴
I really appreciate you guys helping me with the luncheon.
对了 奥列格 我尝了尝食物
And, Oleg, I tried the food,
一点儿也不恶心
and it wasn't gross.
你听到了吗 阿憨
You hear that, Han?
一点儿也不 恶心
Wasn't. Gross.
干了几个小时服务员后
After being a servant for a few hours,
我理解你们需要忍受的事情太多了
I get how much you all have to put up with.
所以我要给你们都加薪
So, I'm giving you all a raise!
太感谢了 阿憨
Thank you so much, Han!
人人都有份吗
Everyone?
他们又不需要药钱生孩子
They don't need drug money for a baby.
但你眼前这位27岁女性 也需要买"药"钱啊
No, but we need drug money for a 27-year-old woman.